Dhanapal Jayapandi

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

11675 Rainwater Dr, Alpharetta, GA 30009

□ 678-666-0066 | 🔏 djay98.github.io | 🖸 djay98 | 💆 djay982

Summary _

Software engineering manager, and architect with 10+ years of professional experience. Solid track record in designing and implementing elegant and pragmatic solutions for enterprise applications. History of excellence in Digital transformation, Cloud, AI/ML, 5G Communication and Networking. A growth mindset is kept by seeking new challenges and learning new skills, languages, and tools. Aim to utilize my analytical and technical expertise to impact core business strategy and results of a growing higher performance organization.

Work Experience _____

Amdocs Inc.

Atlanta, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Oct. 2011 - Present

- Designed and developed a comprehensive platform for Verizon for orchestration, automation, and life cycle management of 5G and next-generation networks.
- Architected a high-performance application to convert HEAT packages to TOSCA packages using Python, Docker and Helm. Now 100x faster than a manual conversion process.
- · Architected and developed an Generic-VNFM to handle life cycle operations of a 5G network functions in a lab environment.
- Designed, architected, and developed a cloud-native business intelligence and reporting platform for AT&T that allows business users to gain AI-driven insights from diverse billing data sources.
- Designed and developed RESTful interfaces for bill payment and bill presentment APIs, increasing performance by 5x.
- Implemented automated deployment pipelines for microservices running as Docker containers using Jenkins, Ansible and Maven.
- Overhauled legacy Amdocs web applications from server-side rendering technologies (JSP/struts) to client-side rendering view technologies leading to increased usability and mobile responsiveness.
- Conceptualized, redesigned, and optimized ETL processor to extract invoices data from billing data feed into NoSQL datastore using Apache Spark, Hadoop and Python.
- Spearheaded development of Mass data load system, MDE, to help business with mass campaigns, adjustments, and BOGO offers for AT&T.
- · Revamped MDE to reduce system coupling; directed parallelized algorithms to improve the performance by 500%.
- Managed product deliverables, project deadlines, system availability, technology infrastructure, system security, and business proposals.
- Promoted Agile transformation efforts to improve team velocity by 2x times instituted retrospectives, continuous integration, code reviews and automated testing.
- · Initiated proof of concept efforts for new technologies and tools to help with pre-sales and eliminate technical debt.
- Led a team of software engineers to design and implement software projects, generating over \$10MM+ in annual revenue.

Amdocs Inc. St. Louis, USA

DEVELOPMENT EXPERT

Oct. 2009 - Sep. 2011

- Designed and developed an intuitive and easy-to-use Amdocs Dispute and Adjustment module for an estimated 50% efficiency gain in operations and potential savings of more than 500K per month to the customer.
- Formulated a maintenance plan to keep the Amdocs Enterprise CRM application running 24x7 in the production system.
- Managed overall service infrastructure focusing on high-availability, business continuity, and system performance.
- · Identified security risks, performance issues, technical debts, and recommended changes to simplify application's on-going maintenance.
- · Mentored junior software developers helping with knowledge on best practices, and CRM implementation.
- · Promoted to Software engineering manager within 24 months due to solid performance and organizational impact.

Amdocs Development Ltd Limassol, Cyprus

SENIOR SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

July. 2006 - Oct. 2009

- · Analyzed new features from customers and proposed technology solutions to implement on top of the existing Amdocs platform.
- Developed and maintained Amdocs CRM application for several T1 service providers.
- Implemented Amdocs CRM v7.5 for a Tier1 company to manage e-service tickets.
- Authored proof-of-concept to show the business value of Amdocs CRM to DishNET, Telstra, and Excelcom.
- · Provided bug fixes, fixed performance issues, optimized queries, and improved Amdocs CRM and OMS product usability.
- · Providing Technical guidance and explaining advanced concepts of Amdocs CRM product to other members in the work area.

Amdocs Development Ltd

Subject Matter Expert Oct. 2004 - Jun. 2006

Limassol, Cyprus

- Designed, developed, and deployed large-scale CRM for Deutsche Telekom and Vodafone UK.
- · Implemented a logging framework for Deutsche Telekom to log messages in Eclipse Common Base Event (CBE) format.
- Analyzed and fixed performance issues and functional defects in the Amdocs CRM product.
- Provided bug fixes for Amdocs eCare Integration APIs.
- Involved in the certification of Orion and Omega release of Amdocs CRM.

HCL Technologies Chennai, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

June. 2003 - Oct. 2004

- Developed DART, Developers Automated Regression Tool, for testing pricing, usage and billing APIs of Convergys Atlys Billing System.
- Enhanced the digital knowledge base of Atlys Billing with latest technologies.

Key Skills.

Languages Java, J2EE, JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES8/ES10), Typescript, Python, GO, Rust, PHP, Perl, Unix Shells, AWK

Backend Spring framework, SpringBoot, Node.js, Express, Django, Flask, Laravel

Frontend Angular, React.js, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass

Databases Oracle, MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, Redis

Cloud & Containers AWS, Azure, Openstack, Openshift, Kubernetes, Helm, Traefik, Rancher

CI/CD/Tools Docker, Ansible, Git, Nexus, Jenkins, Gradle, Maven, Nagios, Vagrant

Systems Red Hat Linux 5/6/7/8, Sun Solaris, IBM AIX, Ubuntu, Weblogic, JBOSS, Apache Tomcat EE, Nginx

Telco 5G development, ONAP, ETSI MANO, AI/ML, ETL, CRM, Order management, Electronic bill payments, Self-service portals,

Domain Knowledge Campaigns

Others Technical leadership

Certifications

2021 **Terraform Associate**, HashiCorp

2020 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Professional, AWS

2020 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, AWS

2020 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS

2019 **SAFe Agilist**, Scaled Agile Framework

2013 **Project Management Professional (PMP), PMI**

2008 Sun Certified Java Developer, J2SE 5.0

2006 Sun Certified Web Component Developer, J2EE 1.4

2005 Sun Certified Java Programmer, J2SE 5.0

Education

College of Engineering, Guindy (Anna University)

Guindy, India

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Jun. 1999 - May. 2003

• Received Gupta Scholarship, 1999 - 2003, for academic excellence in the computer science department.